costar.com 2018-12-28

# CoStar Privacy Policy | CoStar

### 1\. Who We Are

CoStar Realty Information, Inc. is the number one provider of information, analytics and online marketplaces to the commercial real estate industry in the United States and United Kingdom. Some of the information we collect, use and store may be classified as personal information under various laws. collect from you.

### 2\. Personal Information and Application of Privacy Policy

This privacy policy provides users of [www.costar.com](http://www.costar.com/) and services provided by CoStar Realty Information, Inc. and its affiliates (collectively, “CoStar” or “we” or “us”) with information about how CoStar collects, uses and stores personal information.   
Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. This includes items such as your name, email address, IP address, username or other personal identifier. The following section details the specific items of personal data which we collect, use and store.   
Our websites and the products or services licensed to you by us may contain links to other websites operated by third parties. CoStar has no control over, and is not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of, such third party websites and this privacy policy does not apply to those websites. By clicking on third party links, you expressly relieve CoStar from any and all liability arising from your use of such third party sites.   
This privacy policy does not apply to CoStar companies based in the United Kingdom or European Union or to your purchase or license of CoStar UK Limited or any of our other European subsidiaries’ products or services. In such cases, please see the relevant service’s privacy policy located at each applicable website (e.g., the CoStar UK Limited Privacy Policy is available at [ http://www.costar.co.uk/privacy-policy](http://www.costar.co.uk/privacy-policy)). 

### 3\. How We Collect, Use and Store Your Information 

CoStar offers a variety of different services. Below is a list of services we provide and a description of how we collect, use and store personal information we obtain from you in connection with those services. In addition, certain of our uses, collection methods and ways in which we store your information apply to all of our services and are listed at the end of this section.

#### a) CoStar Information and Analytics 

Through our CoStar information services (which includes CoStar Property Professional®, CoStar COMPS Professional®, CoStar Tenant®, CoStar Suite® with Market Analytics, Showcase®, CoStar Connect®, Professional Directory™, CoStar Mobile™, CoStar Go®, CoStar Lease Analysis®, CoStar Lease Comps™, CoStar Property and CoStar For Sale™, and Metropolis™) and analytics services (which includes CoStar Portfolio Strategy™ and Investment Analysis™), we gather personal information from people associated with commercial real estate, including, but not limited to, brokers, tenants, landlords, property owners, and property managers, as well as users and individuals associated with the administration of the license agreement between the firm with whom these individuals are employed or engaged and CoStar. 

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals: 

  * First Name
  * IP Address
  * Photographs
  * Email Address 
  * Device Location
  * Cookie IDs
  * Geographies Viewed 

  * Last Name
  * Business Address
  * Job Title
  * Authentication
  * FaceTime ID
  * Logon Activity
  * Gender

  * Company Name
  * Mobile Number
  * Nickname
  * Username
  * Dates Logged On
  * LinkedIn ID

  * Marketing Preferences
  * Log-in Credentials
  * Telephone Number(s)
  * Password hash (pseudonomized)
  * Properties Viewed 
  * Product Modules Viewed 

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * Extracting information from your CoStar subscription agreement and contract proposals 
  * Documenting information obtained by our CoStar sales and client services people and our other CoStar representatives either through email, over the telephone or at various CoStar meetings or events
  * Cataloguing information as a result of our marketing activity to you
  * Monitoring and logging information relating to your product usage (e.g. property views, log-in activity, Cookie ID’s, IP address, device geolocation)
  * Following your use of social media and other external websites relating to CoStar 

We use personal information for the purpose of:

  * Delivering the CoStar information services
  * Marketing and selling other CoStar products and services 
  * Advising clients of CoStar product enhancements and improvements
  * Training clients
  * Tracking usage and providing appropriate training and product demonstrations to our users and prospects
  * Product development 
  * Identifying unauthorized usage
  * Constructing attendee lists for CoStar events
  * Creating and displaying an entry in the CoStar Professional Directory, including your name, business address, map of address, telephone number, and deals information.
  * Creating and displaying “Dealmakers™” information
  * Developing, testing and maintaining the CoStar Suite® product

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information on CoStar’s servers located in data centers in the United States (on production, development, test, backup and training servers). 

_Google Analytics_

We monitor your website usage in order to identify trends, aggregate statistics, optimize your use of the website and provide a safer environment for purchasing. Examples of the data we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your log-in credentials, your computer connection information (such as browser type and version), your operating system and platform, the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) click stream to, through and from our websites (including date and time), your CoStar-related preferences and the terms you searched for. This section applies to your use of CoStar Property Professional®, CoStar COMPS Professional®, CoStar Tenant®, CoStar Suite® with Market Analytics, CoStar Go®, CoStar Lease Analysis®, CoStar Lease Comps™. 

#### b) CoStar Real Estate Manager™

Through our CoStar Real Estate Manager™ service, including the CoStar Lease Accounting™ module, we gather personal information from client users, client vendors, client customers, and business contacts. 

Client Users

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Email Address
  * IP Addresses

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * User providing this information directly within the CoStar Real Estate Manager application
  * Monitoring and logging information relating to your use of the service 

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information within a SQL server database located in the United States.

Client Vendors and Client Customers 

_Lawful basis for data processing_

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals: 

  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Mailing address
  * Phone number
  * Email address 

We collect this personal information in the following ways: 

  * User providing this information directly within the CoStar Real Estate Manager application

CoStar does not use this personal information; however, the Client Vendors and Client Customers use this information within the CoStar Real Estate Manager application, which is hosted in CoStar’s environment. 

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information within a SQL server database located in the United States.

Business contacts

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Mailing address
  * Phone number
  * Email address 
  * Title

We collect this personal information through an agreement with third party service providers.  
We use this personal information for the purpose of interacting with current and prospective clients, tracking engagement, and for customer support activities. 

_Storage of personal information_

We use a third party service provider to store this personal information. 

_Google Analytics_

We monitor your website usage in order to identify trends, aggregate statistics, optimize your use of the website and provide a safer environment for purchasing. Examples of the data we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your log-in credentials, your computer connection information (such as browser type and version), your operating system and platform, the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) click stream to, through and from our websites (including date and time), your CoStar Real Estate Manager™-related preferences and the terms you searched for. 

#### c) CoStar Private Sale Network™

Through CoStar Private Sale Network™, we gather personal information from brokers that use the service to build listing websites and investors/brokers that register to receive access to a listing website built using the service.

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * First Name
  * Phone Number
  * Address

  * Last Name
  * Fax Number 
  * Province

  * Company Name 
  * Mobile Number
  * County

We collect this personal information from a web form completed by these individuals.

We use this personal information for the purposes of:

  * Sending Brokers invoices
  * Aggregate reporting 

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information within a SQL server database located in the United States. 

#### d) CoStar Brokerage Applications™ 

Through CoStar Brokerage Applications™, we gather personal information from users (or their administrative or support people), primary contacts (e.g., executives, billing contacts or other points of contact), and prospects.

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * First Name
  * Business Phone

  * Company Name
  * Mobile Phone

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * Extracting information from your CoStar subscription agreement, contract proposals, your public website and email signatures
  * Directly requesting information from you for a specific purpose
  * Collecting information volunteered by you (e.g., notifying us of a change of address)
  * Acquiring information through CoStar’s internal customer relationship management database

We use this personal information for the purpose of:

  * Direct communication with a customer/prospect

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information in servers located in the United States.

#### e) CoStar News

Through the CoStar News service, which includes the news service offered in the US and Canada, we gather personal information from current subscribers to CoStar’s information and analytics services as well as other individuals requesting news service access. 

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * First Name
  * Usage Indicator
  * Phone Number

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * Extracting information from your CoStar information subscription agreement, contract proposals, public websites and email signatures
  * Collecting information volunteered by you (e.g., notifying us of a change of address)
  * Acquiring information through CoStar’s internal customer relationship management database

We use this personal information for the purpose of:

  * Populating/updating email lists to send you CoStar News emails 

_Storage of personal information_

We store this information with a third party service provider pursuant to an agreement between us and the service provider.

#### f) CoStar Advertising

Through CoStar Advertising, we gather personal information from prospects, customers and third parties that that service our customers or become part of a transaction (e.g., advertising agencies).

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * First Name
  * Business Phone

  * Company Name
  * Company Address

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * Extracting information from your CoStar agreement, contract proposals, your public website and email signatures
  * Directly requesting information from you for a specific purpose
  * Collecting information volunteered by you (e.g., notifying us of a change of address)
  * Acquiring information through CoStar’s internal customer relationship management database

We use this personal information for the purpose of:

  * Fulfilling the purpose of your agreement to place advertisements on CoStar websites
  * Processing payments

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information on CoStar’s servers located in data centers in the United States.

#### g) Direct Marketing 

Through our direct marketing, we gather personal information from clients and prospective clients of any CoStar product or service, including visitors from our CoStar.com and costargroup.com websites. 

We collect the following types of personal information from these individuals:

  * Company Name
  * Mobile Number

  * Email Address
  * Website Activity

We collect this personal information from a web form completed by these individuals as well as common marketing tags that record website user behavior.

We use this personal information for the purposes of:

  * Website user contact
  * Developing insights about our customers and website visitors
  * Direct marketing email and printed mail campaigns about CoStar’s products and services through our third party email marketing platform

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information with a third party email marketing provider who retains personal data from a particular campaign in respect of every individual who has received that email campaign. Where an individual completes a web-based landing page form, the personal data captured by that form is recorded and retained by a separate third party email marketing provider. In both cases, the personal data captured by the third party on behalf of CoStar is not used for any purpose other than as stated herein. Your personal information may also be stored in our social media network partners, including, Google, Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter. We also store your personal information within our internal customer relationship management system. 

#### h) Listing Brokers and Corporate Tenants and Landlords 

We permit agents to list properties for lease or sale through CoStar Suite® (“Listing Brokers”). We gather Listing Brokers’ personal information through agents, owners, property managers, developers, asset managers and architects. We gather corporate tenants’ (e.g., CEOs, Finance Directors, Facilities coordinators, branch managers) and corporate landlords’ personal information (collectively, “Corporate Tenants and Landlords”).

Listing Brokers

We collect the following types of personal information about Listing Brokers:

  * First Name
  * Fax Number
  * Photograph
  * IP Address

  * Surname
  * Mailing Address
  * Business History
  * Logon History

  * Email Address
  * Job Title
  * Credentials
  * Phone call recordings 

  * Telephone Number(s)
  * Search History
  * Prior Companies

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * From emails or phone calls from clients or other contacts (including, among others, admins, colleagues, joint agent's brochures) with updated contact information 
  * From a Listing Broker’s website or through search engine searches

We use this personal information for the following purposes:

  * Calling and emailing out to contacts to collect listing, deal and other industry data on a monthly basis <
  * Executing outbound marketing campaigns (see "Direct Marketing" section) 
  * Creating workflow spreadsheets and analysis that are used internally 
  * Entering details into CoStar Suite® where those details can be viewed by our subscriber base. In particular those personal details (a) appear in the Professional Directory™ (b) appear in the DealMakers™ section and (c) are attached to specific and relevant building and transactional records in CoStar Suite®.

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information within our internal customer relationship management system, email exchange servers and their archives, paper on desks, personal desktops, internal shared drives and storage devices (e.g., USB sticks). 

Corporate Tenants and Landlords

We collect the following types of personal information about Corporate Tenants and Landlords:

  * Last Name
  * Business Address

We collect this personal information in the following ways:

  * From emails or phone calls from corporate tenants, landlords and building managers 
  * From a Corporate Tenant’s or Landlord’s website or through search engine searches
  * From information originating from third party sources, including, among others: (i) building front desk/concierge/building manager/neighboring tenants, (ii) LinkedIn or other social media (business Facebook page, Twitter), (iii) paid third party providers, (iv) public and freely accessible databases such as state websites and (v) published agent investment brochures and tenancy schedules

We use this personal information for the following purposes:

  * Providing the CoStar Suite® service, which includes a directory visible to everyone who subscribes to the service
  * Calling relevant corporate tenants to capture or confirm occupancy, leasing information, and other commercial real estate data
  * Entering details into CoStar Suite® where those details can be viewed by our subscriber base. In particular, those personal details are attached to specific and relevant building and transactional records in CoStar Suite®

_Storage of personal information_

We store your personal information within our internal customer relationship management system, email exchange servers and their archives, paper on desks, personal desktops, internal shared drives and storage devices (e.g., USB sticks). 

The following uses, collection methods and ways we store your information are applicable to all of our services:

#### (1) Cookies

Some areas of our websites use and require that you accept "cookies." Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer or other device to keep track of settings or data for a particular website. Cookies make it possible and easier for you to access and use certain areas of these websites. If you have disabled cookies from within your browser, or if you are running third-party software that intercepts or deletes cookies, you may not be able to visit certain areas of these websites. In addition, CoStar’s third party vendors may collect information about you when using our websites through the use of cookies. For example, third-party advertising companies, such as Google, use cookies to serve advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you across the Internet based on your past visits to our websites and other websites. In particular, the Google Analytics feature implemented and used on certain of our websites includes remarketing and interest-based display advertising where Google uses a cookie to remember information about your visit and deliver more relevant ads. In addition, our websites may share statistical and behavioral data about visitors to our websites with these third-party advertising companies for the purpose of managing and targeting advertisements on our websites and/or on other websites. Visitors can opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s [Ad Settings](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

#### (2) Anonymous Data

We also collect anonymized details about visitors to our websites for the purposes of aggregate statistics or reporting purposes. However, no single individual will be identifiable from the anonymized details we collect for these purposes.. 

#### (3) Suppression Lists

In the case of product information newsletters or direct or electronic mailing lists, you will be able to "unsubscribe" to these mailings at any time. If you choose to do so, CoStar will store your first name, last name and email address that it has collected in an internal database and use it only for the purpose of periodically referencing the list to ensure that we do not contact you. 

#### (4) Biometric and Geolocation Information

Some areas of our websites may require you to provide facial images, facial geometry, fingerprints and geolocation information at the time you log in to use certain CoStar services. CoStar will securely store this information on CoStar servers located in the United States and this information will only be accessed by authorized CoStar employees. Your biometric and geolocation information is used to authenticate you as the user of certain CoStar services, maintain a secure session and detect potential abuse and fraudulent use of such services.

### 4\. Accuracy

We will, as necessary, keep your personal information accurate and complete based on the information provided to us. However, information contained in files that are dormant or have been closed will not be actively updated or maintained by CoStar.  
If you believe that any of your personal information held by us is not correct, you may request an update of that information by sending a written request to: Privacy Officer, Jonathan Coleman, via mail at 1331 L Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 or email at [privacy@costar.com](mailto:privacy@costar.com) or our Data Protection Officer by email at [gdpr@costar.co.uk.](mailto:gdpr@costar.co.uk)

### 5\. Data Processing

CoStar’s global corporate affiliates assist us in supplying and providing services to our customers. In addition, CoStar retains subcontractors, agents, advisors and suppliers to assist us in our business. CoStar may permit these affiliates and third parties to access your personal information in order to assist us in providing services; however, these parties must keep your personal information confidential and must not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for CoStar. 

### 6\. Data Sharing

Circumstances may arise where we are required to disclose your personal information to third parties for purposes other than to support your customer relationship with CoStar. Those circumstances include:

(i) in connection with a corporate divestiture or dissolution where we sell all or a portion of our business or assets (including our associated customer lists containing your personal information); 

(ii) if disclosure is permitted or required by law (for example, in connection with judicial proceedings or governmental investigations); or

(iii) to identify possible violations of CoStar’s Terms of Use or a separate license agreement and to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities that may be violating your rights, our rights or the rights of others. 

### 7\. International Transfers

To the extent personal information is collected by CoStar or any of its affiliates in the European Economic Area, we will transfer, in accordance with applicable law, personal information that we collect from you to third party data processors located in countries that are outside of the European Economic Area, specifically, to CoStar Realty Information, Inc., in connection with the above purposes. CoStar and its relevant affiliates have entered into an intra-company agreement that sets forth the operational processes and meets the European Commission’s requirements of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data outside of the European Economic Area. Whenever we transfer your personal information out of the European Economic Area, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by transferring your personal information to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal information by the European Commission or we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission (such as the Standard Contractual Clauses) which give personal data the same protection that it has in Europe.   
Please be aware that other countries which are outside the United States or the European Economic Area may not offer the same level of data protection as the United States or the United Kingdom, although our collection, storage and use of your personal information will continue to be governed by this privacy policy. 

### 8\. Consent

You are giving CoStar your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information for the purposes of providing you with products and services by giving us your personal information for those purposes. We use an opt-out standard for communications with you about our products and services and other products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please contact us by e-mail to [support@costar.com](mailto:support@costar.com). In addition, you can select unsubscribe on any of our electronic email marketing communications to you. If you opt-out of marketing communications, CoStar will still contact you in connection with providing you with the products and services you have requested from us. 

### 9\. Your Rights

You have the right to ask us to provide you with copies of personal information that we hold about you at any time. In addition, you have the right to update or correct any out-of-date or inaccurate personal information that we hold about you (in accordance with applicable data protection laws). If you would like to access and make changes to information that you have provided to us in connection with your online account, please log into your account and review and correct the information that you provided. If you would like assistance in accessing or correcting other information, please write to either (a) our Privacy Officer, Jonathan Coleman, via mail at 1331 L Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 or email at [privacy@costar.com](mailto:privacy@costar.com) or (b) our Data Protection Officer by email at [gdpr@costar.co.uk](mailto:gdpr@costar.co.uk).   
If you want us to stop using or to delete your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@costar.com](mailto:privacy@costar.com) and tell us why. In certain circumstances, we may not be able to stop using your personal information but, if that is the case, we'll let you know and tell you why. 

### 10\. Retention

CoStar retains personal information as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected and as required to comply with business and legal requirements (e.g., to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes (legal or otherwise) or enforce our agreements). The length of time CoStar retains personal information varies and may extend beyond the end of the individual’s relationship with CoStar. 

### 11\. Security

We take steps to protect the security of the personally identifiable information we collect, including, for example, physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to or through our websites; any such transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.  
Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. 

### 12.No Data Regarding Children

Although our websites can technically be viewed by children, we do not knowingly request personally identifiable information from them nor do our websites publish content that is targeted to children. No information should be submitted to, or posted on, our websites by visitors under the age of 18. 

### 13\. Global Privacy Considerations

Personal information collected by CoStar, where applicable, may be stored and processed in the United States or in any other country where CoStar or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or third-party service providers maintain facilities. When you provide personal information to CoStar, you consent to the processing and transfer of your information within the United States and around the world. We follow applicable data protection laws when transferring personal information.  
European Economic Area Privacy Rights  
In the European Economic Area, CoStar will process your personal information for the legitimate interests of CoStar, or, when needed, with your explicit consent. If you have provided consent for the processing of your personal information, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time, which will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent was withdrawn. If you wish to have more information regarding the legitimate interests assessment we have conducted in order to reach this conclusion please contact us at [gdpr@costar.co.uk](mailto:gdpr@costar.co.uk).  
You have the right to request access to and rectification or erasure of your personal information, as well as the right to restrict processing, object to processing, and under certain circumstances the right to data portability. You may do so by contacting CoStar’s Data Protection Officer at [gdpr@costar.co.uk](mailto:gdpr@costar.co.uk). You have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority if you believe that we have not complied with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation with regard to your personal information. 

### 14\. Amendment of CoStar’s Practices and Privacy Policy

We will from time to time review and revise our privacy practices and this privacy policy. Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date of the revised privacy policy as well as to existing information held by CoStar. Please refer to our website for the most current version of our privacy policy. 

### 15\. Questions and Complaints

We have appointed a Privacy Officer and Data Protection Officer to investigate and respond to privacy issues and to be accountable for our compliance with this privacy policy. If you have questions about access to your personal information held by us or about our collection, use, storage or disclosure of your personal information, or if you wish to make a privacy-related complaint, you may contact either (a) our Privacy Officer, Jonathan Coleman, via mail at 1331 L Street NW, Washington, DC 20005 or email at [privacy@costar.com](mailto:privacy@costar.com) or (b) our Data Protection Officer by email at [gdpr@costar.co.uk](mailto:gdpr@costar.co.uk). 

#### Last Updated: July 23, 2018
